

# Contact

LinkedIn: jaroslaw-sipika E-mail: jaroslaw.sipika@gmail.com Phone: +48 663090542 Personal webpage: justasecond.pl Github: JaroslawSipika

#### Technical skills

- Java
- SQL
- SpringBoot
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Python

#### Soft skills

- Communicativeness
- Responsibility
- Discipline
- Teamwork

# Languages

- English B2
- German B1

# Jarosław Sipika

Computer Science Student/Assistant Geotechnical Engineer at STRABAG

I am currently a student of the last year of extramural first-cycle studies in Computer Science at the Cracow University of Technology at the Faculty of Electrical and Computer Engineering. During my studies at university, I have the opportunity to develop my knowledge in the broadly understood IT industry, which mainly concerns the construction and operation of operating systems, computer systems architecture, programming in object-oriented programming languages, databases and computer networks, and computer graphics. I efficiently use the acquired knowledge in my current company by writing scripts that help optimize processes in my daily work. I develop programming skills in Java, Python and VBA.

Five years ago I obtained the title of Master of Science in Civil Engineering at the AGH University of Science and Technology. I had the opportunity to develop my language skills during Erasmus exchange in Germany during my education.

My employment history is about a job related to my civil engineering education. I am currently working as an Assistant Geotechnical Engineer at Strabag in Cracow. I efficiently use computer software related to the construction industry. I also obtained building qualifications for designing.

During my professional work, I was able to develop a number of soft skills such as the ability to work under time pressure and resistance to stress, communication and the ability to work in a team. I am characterized by great work organization and the ability to work in an international team.

## **Projects**

- 1. justasecond.pl Personal webpage.
  - Website is written using HTML, CSS and JS
- 2. GEOTUR Internet service supporting the planning of mountain trips.
  - The application is based on the REST API architecture, which allows the user to manage his own mountain routes, create photo galleries and enable communication with other people.
    Technologies used in the project: Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, Maven, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- FITNESS GOLD Internet service supporting the management of a fitness club.
  - The application is based on the REST API architecture, enabling customers to efficiently book sports activities and equipment. The website facilitates the coordination of the work of the fitness club staff. Technologies used in the project: Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, Maven, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Optimization of work tools by creating scripts in Python and VBA (civil engineering industry).

## Work experience

Assistant Geotechnical Engineer at Strabag

October 2020 - up to now

Assistant Geotechnical Engineer at Jacobs

September 2018 - October 2020



#### Assistant Engineer at JPL Project

February 2018 - September 2018

#### Geotechnical Engineer IMG Monitoring

September 2016 - February 2018

## Education

## Computer Science, Cracow University of Technology

September 2017 - up to now

Master of Science, Civil Engineering, Specialization: Geotechnics and Underground Construction, University of Science and Technology at Cracow

March 2015 - September 2017

## Civil Engineering, RWTH Aachen University

February 2016 - July 2016

# Bachelor of Science, Civil Engineering University of Science and Technology at Cracow

September 2011 - March 2015

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realising the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).